# Ganiyat Abiodun Olajobi

Huddersfield • +447448343677 • ganiyat\_olajobi@outlook.com

# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Adaptable and self-motivated QA Test Engineer with over one (1) year experience providing first-class results. Meets job demands and deadlines through diligent work-ethic and dedication to quality. Experience in writing test cases, creates test plans and identifies use cases. Comprehensive understanding of full software development lifecycle. Working comfortably and collaboratively in a fast-paced and target-driven environment, communicate complex issues simply and clearly, and work on own initiative to achieve own targets/deadlines and shared team goals.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

QA Test Engineer, 11/2020 - Current

**LEMP** - London

- Raising any potential gaps in test reports with QA Team manager during the testing cycle.
- Helping support team during fault investigations.
- Communicating technical issues with multiple team members.
- Ensuring testing systems meets assigned acceptance criteria, rectifying issues swiftly and accurately.
- Demonstrated expertise across functional and non-functional testing, including estimation, test planning and execution and defect reporting.
- Collaborated effectively with engineering teams to improve quality assurance processes through diligent testing.
- Wrote high-performing test cases, procedures, and plans, gathering required data for targeted QA improvements.

**Senior Associate, Audit, Compliance, & Accountancy**, 01/2017 - 09/2020

Hamzat Subair & Co - Lagos, Nigeria

Performing multiple financial audit exercises, writing up of books of accounts for clients, secondment as company accountant to client

- Managed and supervised associates on clients' engagements
- Prepared management control reports, company's final accounts, bank reconciliation statements and client's cash books and generating of trial balance.
- Gathered audit evidence to support analysis and findings across wider assignment work.
- Crosschecked audit files with associated documentation to ensure appropriate levels of supporting evidence.
- Provided accurate, reliable administrative support, keeping, and filing precise, detailed audit records.
- Demonstrated keen financial understanding, aiding insightful client and wider project support.
- Collaborated effectively with clients to understand and offer solutions to challenges and needs.

Associate, Compliance & Payroll management, 01/2013 - 12/2016Hamzat Subair & Co, Federal Inland Revenue Service, FIRS - Lagos,

#### **CORE SKILLS**

- Issue tracking and project management tools, especially Jira.
- Bug reporting workflows
- Testing methodologies: Manual, Functional, Unit, Integration, Black Box, Regression, Acceptance testing and Basic Knowledge in Automation Testing.
- Test strategies, test cases and test plans
- Processes Agile Methodology, Waterfall Model, Software Development Lifecycle SDLC and Software Test Lifecycle STLC.
- Microsoft Excel (Pivot Tables, Lookups & Logical functions), Word, Access and PowerPoint for report writing exercise.
- Client facing skills for building and maintaining client-business relationship
- Excellent communication skills
- Good knowledge and hands on weka and Tableau software.
- Attention to detail

# **EDUCATION**

**Master of Science**: Financial technology, 09/2021

#### **University of Huddersfield -**

Huddersfield, United Kingdom Modules includes, Artificial Intelligence and Mobility, Data Analysis and Visualisation, Managing Big Data, Distributed Ledger Technologies, Global Professional, Financial Reporting and Company Performance, Principles of Finance, Managing Employee Relations, Research Methods.

Bachelor of Science: Economics &
Development Studies, 07/2007
Igbinedion University - Edo, Nigeria
Final Modules include Advance
Microeconomics, Applied Economics,
International Trade Theory, Comparative
Economic System, Energy and Petroleum
Economics, Health Economics, Advanced
Macroeconomics, Applied Econometrics,
International Finance, Applied Statistics,
Economics Planning, Taxation and Fiscal

#### Nigeria

- Performing internal control compliance exercises, multiple financial audit exercises, writing up of books of accounts for clients, Acted as Tax audit monitoring agent for Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS).
- Preparation of bank reconciliation statements for clients, Preparation
  of cash books and TB for clients, secondment as compliance officer
  for a client.

# **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Investigated, identified, and reconciled account discrepancies totaling £10,000 in company savings.
- Sourced, negotiated, and secured Audit contract, resulting in £5,000 annual savings.
- Improved Payment Voucher reviews by successfully handling customer complaints and implementing monthly staff training.
- Recognised by management for hard working behaviour, ability to learn quickly and excellent collaboration skill leading to increased Salary.

Policy, Research Projects.

# **INTERESTS**

Technology, Finance, Music, Socialising, Travelling, Reading, and spending time with family and friends.